HAI DANG

hai.dang@uni-bayreuth.de

Doctoral HCI Researcher (2nd Year)

I'm a Ph.D. candidate in the **HCI+AI** research group with strong **quantitative research skills** and a record of publications at top-tier peer reviewed conferences. I design **interactive co-creative systems** that enable users to create more expressive digital content. I conduct **user studies** to understand pitfalls in the status-quo process of humans interacting with imperfect AIs.

EDUCATION

since 2020 Ph.D. in Human Computer Interaction

University of Bayreuth, Bayreuth Germany

Department of Computer Science, Advisor: Daniel Buschek Research Focus: Designing interactive co-creative systems.

2018-2020 Master of Science in Computer Science

University of Munich, Munich

Department of Computer Science

Thesis - Representational Learning for Exploring Input Spaces in HCI

2013-2018 Bachelor of Science in Media Informatics

University of Munich, Munich

Department of Computer Science

Thesis - Deep Conformance Checking: Efficient Estimation of Alignment Based Fitness.

2016-2017 Bachelor of Science in Media Informatics

Yonsei University, Seoul

Department of Computer Science

Year Abroad

SELECTED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

since 2020 Research Assistant, University of Bayreuth

Building interactive co-creative systems.

- · Using generative models to improve user interfaces [P.2].
- · Improve user interface for generative models [P.1].

2020-2020 Research Intern: HCI+AI (5 Months), University of Bayreuth

Developed Visual Analytics tool for Motion Sensor data. (Python + ReactJS) [P.2].

2019-2019 Machine Learning Developer (2 Months), SWM, Munich

Built and deployed an end-to-end electricity consumption prediction model. (PyTorch)

2017-2019 Software Developer / Data Scientist, Celonis, Munich

Developed Python Data Push API for the Celonis Business Intelligence Cloud Platform

SKILLS

User Research: Online Surveys, Computational Analysis Methods

Expert Interviews, Think-Aloud-Protocol, Statistical Analysis

Programming Languages: Python (advanced), JavaScript (advanced)

Frameworks: PyTorch (advanced), Tensorflow (prior experience)

React (advanced), D3js (fundamentals)

TEACHING ASSISTANT

2021 Creating Intelligent Interactive Systems, University of Bayreuth

Introduction to Machine Learning on Mobile devices

Undergraduate/Graduate level course, with 37 students (Instructor: Daniel Buschek)

2020 Intelligent User Interfaces, University of Bayreuth

Introduction to Web Applications using SvelteJS

Undergraduate level course, with 59 students (Instructor: Daniel Buschek)

Creating Intelligent Interactive Systems, University of Bayreuth

Introduction to Machine Learning on Mobile devices

Undergraduate/Graduate level course, with 21 students (Instructor: Daniel Buschek)

2016 **Programming Multi Media Applications**, University of Munich

Introduction to Python Development for Games.

Undergraduate level course, with 116 students (Instructor: Prof. Heinrich Hussmann)

PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE AND WORKSHOP PUBLICATIONS

- 2022 P.1 Hai Dang, Lukas Mecke, Daniel Buschek. 2022. GANSlider: How Users Control Generative Models for Images using Multiple Sliders with and without Feedforward Information. (to appear CHI '22). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA.
- 2021 P.2 Hai Dang and Daniel Buschek. 2021. GestureMap: Supporting Visual Analytics and Quantitative Analysis of Motion Elicitation Data by Learning 2D Embeddings. In Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI '21). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 317, 1–12.
 - P.3 Daniel Buschek, Lukas Mecke, Florian Lehmann, **Hai Dang** 2021. Nine Potential Pitfalls when Designing Human-AI Co-Creative Systems. In *HAI-GEN Workshop at IUI'21* (*IUI'21*). In Proceedings of the ACM IUI 2021 Workshops, April 13-17, 2021.

SELECTED PROJECTS

- 2021 Search Engine for digitalized Floor Plans 48h TUM.ai Makeathon,
 - · Lead development of an interactive search engine for digitalized floor plans.
 - · Created a dataset with hand-drawn floor plan shapes.
 - · Embedded floor plans using a convolutional Autoencoder and performed Nearest-Neighbor search.
- 2020 Ensemble Knowledge Graph Embedding Seminar: Group Project,
 - · Reimplemented ConvE (Dettmers et al. 2018) and improved computation time by 30% by using vectorization for masking operation.
 - · Managed and monitored machine learning models and remote training clouds using MIFlow and DVC.
- 2020 Evaluation of Consumer Grade BCI Devices Seminar: Group Project,
 - · Applied basic signal processing techniques on the raw EEG recordings to extract alpha and theta frequencies that characterize the cognitive workload.
 - · Trained multiple classifiers from the SciKit library to differentiate between various workload levels.
- 2019 Development of an Interactive Sleep Monitoring Device, Seminar: Group Project
 - · Built the analytics backend to collect and analyze sleep data.
 - · Designed the communication protocol between the device and the analytics backend.

2019 Power Efficient High Performance Computing - Seminar: Group Project,

- · Developed a recurrent neural network model for the prediction of energy consumption.
- · Achievement: Won the class competition for most accurate predictions by employing an autoregressive recurrent neural network.

VOLUNTEERING

2021/22 Education Team Lead, TUM.ai

Leading the TUM.ai AI School initiative where we teach foundational AI knowledge to aspiring students. Our goal is to give interdisciplinary teams a common understanding and vocabulary to discuss and successfully implement AI projects.

2021 Recruitment Lead — Community Building, TUM.ai

TUM.ai connects students and all relevant stakeholders to facilitate the application of AI across domains to drive positive societal impact through interdisciplinary projects.

Web Chair - IUI 2022, ACM, Association for Computing Machinery
ACM IUI is where the Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) community meets the Artificial Intelligence (AI) community.